talent.me 2014-02-09

# Privacy

Your privacy is our top concern. We work hard to earn and keep your trust, so we adhere to the following principles to protect your privacy:

This privacy policy covers [www.Talent.me](https://talent.me/) and Talent.me Facebook App accessed via [http://apps.facebook.com/talent.me](http://apps.facebook.com/talentme) (hereinafter collectively “Talent.me”). It does not, however, apply to entities that Talent.me does not own or control. By using or accessing Talent.me, you agree to our privacy practices outlined here.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage. By continuing to use the Talent.me after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on the Talent.me, you are consenting to the changes.

**1\. Personal Information Collected**    
The purpose of Talent.me is to permit Users to voluntarily provide information about themselves for the purposes of developing, maintaining and enhancing a network of professional contacts. You willingly provide us certain personal information, which we collect in order to allow you to benefit from Talent.me. If you have any hesitation about providing such information to us and/or having such information displayed on Talent.me or otherwise used in any manner permitted in this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, you should not become a member of the Talent.me community.

We collect your personal information in the following ways:

**Registration**  
In order to become a User; you must first create an account on Talent.me using Talent.me’s Facebook App. While creating an account using Facebook Connect, you may be required to provide the following contact information, which you recognize and expressly acknowledge is personal information allowing others, including Talent.me, to identify you: name, email address, country, ZIP/postal code, a brief summary of your professional background, and a password chosen by you. We may also collect other information that is visible on your Facebook profile when permitted by Facebook's Terms of Use as well as additional information that you chose to allow Facebook to provide to Talent.me during registration process. This information may include, but is not limited to, your name, your age, your e-mail address, the location of your computer or handheld device, your profile picture, gender, and the pictures and names of your Facebook "friends", as well as other basic information regarding your Facebook "friends" that may be provided by Facebook to Talent.me. 

**Profile Information**  
Once you become a User, you may provide additional information in the Profile section describing your talents, professional and educational experiences, and networking objectives. You may also provide demographic information such as age, gender, relationship status, interests/hobbies. You also have the ability to upload photos. Please be aware that all users may view your photos. Providing additional information beyond what is required at registration to become a User is entirely optional, but enables you to better identify yourself and find new opportunities in the Talent.me system to build and leverage your professional network. Any information you provide at registration or in the Profile section that is not personally identifiable may be used in the same manner and extent to which other information that is not personally identifiable is permitted to be used hereunder, including for the purpose of serving advertisements through the service. If you opt-out you may lose the potential benefit of being a User, including receiving ads that are more targeted to your interests.

**Contacts Information**  
We offer contact importer tools to help you upload your friends' addresses so that you can find your friends on Talent.me, and invite your contacts that do not have accounts to join. In order to invite others to connect with you directly in Talent.me, you may use the Talent.me services to invite them if they are a User, or enter their names and email addresses. This information will be used by Talent.me to send your friend email invitations on your behalf including a message that you write. The names and email addresses of people that you invite will be used only to send your invitation and reminders. If you give us your password to retrieve those contacts, we will not store your password after you have uploaded your contacts' information.

You may also choose to manually enter or upload data about your contacts into the private “My contacts” section of Talent.me. All information that you enter or upload about your contacts will be covered by the same terms of this privacy policy as cover your own information.

**Customer Service**  
Talent.me may collect information such as your name and email address through the Talent.me website or through the Customer Service website in order to, among other things, accurately categorize and respond to a customer's inquiry and deliver appropriate service levels.

**Cookies**  
Like most websites, Talent.me uses cookies and web log files to track site usage. A cookie is a tiny data file which resides on your computer which allows Talent.me to recognize you as a User when you return to the Talent.me website using the same computer and web browser. If your browser settings do not allow cookies, you will not be able to use the Talent.me website. Like the information you enter at registration or in your Profile, cookie and log file data is used to customize your experience on our website. 

One type of cookie, known as a “persistent” cookie, is set once you've logged in to your Talent.me account. The next time you visit the Talent.me website, the persistent cookie will allow us to recognize you as an existing User by your email address and password, so you will not need to log in before using the service. In order to access or change any of your private information (like a credit card number), however, you must log in securely again with your password even if your computer contains your persistent cookie.

Another type of cookie we utilize is a session ID cookie. A session ID cookies is used to enable certain features of Talent.me, to better understand how you interact with Talent.me and to monitor aggregate usage by Talent.me Users and web traffic routing on Talent.me. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from Talent.me and then close your browser. 

We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing User preferences and tracking User trends. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Unfortunately, if your browser settings do not allow cookies or you opt to refuse all cookies, you may not be able to use the Talent.me. Talent.me does not store personally identifiable information in the cookies.

In the course of serving advertisements or optimizing services to our Users, we may allow authorized third parties to place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. Any information provided to third parties through such cookies will not be personally identifiable but may provide general segment information, e.g. your industry or geographic location, your occupation, or information about your professional or educational background, for greater customization of your user experience. The use of cookies set by these third parties is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

**Web Beacons**  
We allow other companies, called ad networks, to serve advertisements to Users. Ad networks include third party ad servers, ad agencies, ad technology vendors and research firms. Talent.me may “target” some ads to Users that fit a certain general profile - for example, “product managers in Texas.” Talent.me does NOT use personally identifiable information to target ads.

To deliver these ads properly, Talent.me may include a file, called a web beacon, from these ad networks within pages served by Talent.me so the networks may provide anonymized, aggregated auditing, research and reporting for advertisers as well as to target ads to you while you visit other websites.

Because your web browser must request these advertisements and web beacons from the ad network's servers, these companies can view, edit or set their own cookies, just as if you had requested a web page from their site.

These general targets may also be used by ad networks to display targeted ads on other websites as a substitute for random, irrelevant ads. Talent.me does not provide personally identifiable information to any advertiser or any other third party.

**Log files, IP addresses and information about your computer**  
Due to the communications standards on the Internet, when you visit Talent.me we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave Talent.me. We also receive the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system and type of web browser you are using, email patterns, as well as the name of your ISP. This information is used to analyze overall trends to help us improve Talent.me. The linkage between your IP address and your personally identifiable information is not shared with third-parties without your permission or except when required by law.

**Consent to Talent.me Processing Information About You**  
Certain information you provide to Talent.me may reveal, or allow others to identify, your nationality, ethnic origin, religion or other aspects of your private life, and more generally about you. Please be aware that in providing information to Talent.me for the purposes of opening your user account, you are expressly and voluntarily accepting the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and Talent.me's User Agreement. The supplying of all such information by you to Talent.me, including all information deemed “sensitive” by applicable law, is entirely voluntary on your part. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, but please note that your withdrawal of consent will not be retroactive.

**Rights to Access, Correct and Eliminate Information About You**  
You have a right to access, modify, correct and eliminate the data about you which has been collected pursuant to your decision to become a User. If you update any of your information, we may keep a copy of the information which you originally provided to us in our archives for uses documented herein.  
We take your rights seriously and encourage you to use them if you deem this to be appropriate. You may exercise these rights by emailing us at 

_[legal@talent.me](mailto:legal@talent.me)_

 or contacting us at:  
Talent.me  
Attn: Privacy Policy Issues  
3507 Bayshore Blvd Suite 1201  
Tampa, FL 33629  
United States of America 

**2\. Uses of personal information**    
Talent.me is an online service dedicated to helping all types of professionals to tap into their friend’s social network and search for career opportunities. The personally identifiable information you choose to provide on our website is used to help you describe yourself to other Users, to send you newsletters, as well as fulfill your order of a premium or sponsored membership. Other information, that does not personally identify you as an individual, is collected by Talent.me from Users (such as, for example, patterns of utilization) and is exclusively owned by Talent.me. This information can be utilized by Talent.me in such manner as Talent.me, in its sole discretion, deems appropriate.

**Teaming with Other Organizations to Offer Combined and Other Services**  
Talent.me may offer our services in connection with other websites (including updates about the Talent.me service) or may team with marketing partners, affiliated companies, and other online services to give you the combined results of both services or additional services and benefits (“Partners”).

We only work with trusted Partners. To report any suspected misuse of information contact: [legal@Talent.me](mailto:legal@talent.me). Talent.me is not responsible for your use of or inability to use any services or products of Partners, including the content, accuracy, or reliability of such applications and their privacy practices.

**Talent.me Communications**  
Talent.me will communicate with you through email and notices posted on Talent.me or through other means available via Facebook. These include a series of welcome emails, which help inform new Users about various features of the service. Please be aware that you will always receive certain emails from Talent.me related to the proper functioning of your account, such as email notices when another User in your network endorses you on Talent.me. 

Talent.me, and/or our Partners, may regularly send out newsletters, weekly status emails, or promotional emails. Talent.me may send you promotional information unless you have opted out of receiving such information. You can change your e-mail and contact preferences at any time by amending your email notification choices. In newsletters and weekly status emails, Talent.me and/or our Partner may inform you, among other things, about new features, about your events in the upcoming week, about specific personal statistics from the respective past calendar week (i.e. the number of hits on your Profile, whether you have new contacts to be confirmed and/or new private messages, etc.), or about education content. You may choose to unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time by sending an email to the link provided at the end of each newsletter. 

**Online Directory:**  
We utilize an online directory so that users may find each other on our Web site. Within our directory we will display your name and email address. Since this directory is a major function of our Web site, if you do not want to be part of the directory, you should not register on Talent.me. 

**Customized Content**  
Information provided to Talent.me is also used to customize your experience on our website. For example, when you login to your account we will display the screen names of new Users who have recently joined your network.

**Sharing Information with Third Parties**  
Talent.me takes the privacy of Users very seriously. We do not share, sell, rent, trade or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties other than as disclosed within this privacy policy. We will only share your personally identifiable information with third parties to carry out your instructions or to provide specific services or information. For instance, we use a credit card processing company to bill Users for subscription fees. These third parties do not retain, share, or store any personally identifiable information except to provide these services and they are bound by confidentiality agreements, which limit their use of such information.

**Feedback.**  
We use a third party service provider to host our feedback page. You may submit contact information, such as your name, address, telephone number, or email address, in connection with feedback, concerns, complaints, questions, or technical support. Such information is used only to respond to those inquiries and is governed by this Privacy Policy.

We may provide aggregated anonymous data about the usage of our services to third parties for such purposes as we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate, including to prospective advertisers on Talent.me. We may segment our Users by role (i.e. product managers, vice presidents), industry, geographic location, or company.

**Surveys and Polls**  
As a User, you will receive requests to participate in market research including polls and surveys submitted by other Talent.me members. If you participate in surveys and polls offered through our website, the information you provide may be visible to others using Talent.me. 

**Forums/Chats/Blogs**  
If you post a message or use a bulletin board on Talent.me, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you choose to provide there can be read, collected, or used by other Users of these forums, as well as third parties, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. Talent.me is not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

**Testimonials and Advertisement Placed through Talent.me**  
If you provide any testimonials about Talent.me or place advertisements through Talent.me, we may post those testimonials and examples of advertisements you place in connection with Talent.me's promotion of its service to third parties, which testimonials and advertisements may include your name and other personal information that you have provided. We do obtain the clients consent prior to posting their name along with their testimonial. 

**Communications to other Users**  
Many emails you initiate through Talent.me, e.g., an invitation sent to a non-User, may list your email address and name in the header of the message. 

**Legal Disclaimer**  
It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information when required by law, such as responses to civil or criminal subpoenas, or other requests by law enforcement personnel. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, subpoena, or other legal process or request to Talent.me brought in any country throughout the world, or to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

**Disclosures to others**  
We may also disclose your personal and other information you provide, to another third party as part of a reorganization or a sale of the assets of a Talent.me division or company. Any third party to which we transfer or sell Talent.me's assets will have the right to continue to use the personal and other information that you provide to us. You will be notified via email or prominent notice on our website for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

**3\. Your Information Choices**    
**Accessing and Changing Your Account Information**  
You can review the personal information you provided us and make any desired changes to the information you publish, or to the settings for your Talent.me account including your email, and contact preferences, at any time by logging in to your account and accessing the “My Updates” section. Please be aware that even after your request for a change is processed, Talent.me may, for a time, retain residual information about you in its backup and/or archival copies of its database.

**Closing Your Account**  
If you want to stop using your account you may deactivate it or delete it. When you deactivate an account, no user will be able to see it, but it will not be deleted. We save your profile information (friends, photos, interests, etc.) in case you later decide to reactivate your account. Many users deactivate their accounts for temporary reasons and in doing so are asking us to maintain their information until they return to Talent.me. You will still have the ability to reactivate your account and restore your profile in its entirety. When you delete an account, it is permanently deleted. You should only delete your account if you are certain you never want to reactivate it. We may retain certain data contributed by you if we believe it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law.

**4\. Your Obligations**    
As a User, you have certain obligations toward the other Users with whom you will be communicating. Certain of these obligations are imposed by applicable law and regulations, and others have become commonplace in user-friendly communities of like-minded members, such as Talent.me:

Any violation of these guidelines may lead to the restriction, suspension or termination of your account by Talent.me, as we take these principles seriously and consider them to be the basis on which our Users adhere to the Talent.me website and the services which it offers.

**5\. Important Information**    
**Minors**  
Children are not eligible to use our service and we ask that minors (under the age of 18) do not submit any personal information to us or use the service.

**No information from children under age 13**  If you are under age 13, please do not attempt to register for Talent.me or provide any personal information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under age 13, please contact us through [this help page](https://talent.me/about/contact.php).

By becoming a User, you have given us your express and informed consent to transfer the data which you provide to us to the United States and to process it in the United States.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we change how we use your personally identifiable information, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. If we decide to change our privacy practices, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and/or other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

If you use the Talent.me service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on our site, you hereby provide your consent to the changed practices.

**6\. Security**    
In order to secure your personal information, access to your data on Talent.me is password-protected, and sensitive data (such as credit card information) is protected by SSL encryption when it is exchanged between your web browser and the Talent.me web site. To protect any data you store on our servers we also regularly audit our system for possible vulnerabilities and attacks and we use a tier-one secured-access data center. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that emails and instant messaging and similar means of communication with other users of Talent.me are not encrypted and we strongly request you not to communicate any confidential information through these means.

**7\. How to contact us**    
If you have questions or comments about this privacy policy, please email us at:  

**or contact us at:**  
Talent.me  
Attn: Privacy Policy Issues  
3507 Bayshore Blvd Suite 1201  
Tampa, FL 33629
